SUMMARY

I'm a creative developer excited about coding rich, elegant narrative experiences that engage news audiences through personal relevance and delight. My drive to always find better ways to tackle problems recently led me to learn programming and web development through a 12 week immersive course at General Assembly.

EXPERIENCE

NPR, Washington, DC

January 2005-December 2013

Librarian II

Responsible for investigating story ideas, fact finding and problem solving in support of reporters, producers and editors working on daily broadcast and digital news platforms.

- Collected and analyzed data for web graphics
- Fact-checked and contributed to *This Is NPR* published by Chronicle Books
- Contributed to NPR corporate history timeline for new headquarters lobby
- Received "Penguin Award" for innovative power plant outage data gathering
- 2012 Elections unit detail: Proposed and independently developed custom candidate database; assisted with election night special

Broadcast Librarian L

- Managed collection of commercial and rare audio for use in production; archived broadcast material
- Contributed to *Playback* archival news podcast; interviewed Susan Stamberg

National Security Archive, Washington, DC

Indexer/Abstractor, July 2005-October 2006

Summarized and organized large sets of declassified government documents pertaining to major 20^{th} century foreign policy events for ProQuest's Digital National Security Archive.

George Mason University, Arlington, VA

Reference Librarian, 2004-2005 (part-time)

SKILLS

Ruby on Rails, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML/CSS, PostgreSQL

EDUCATION

St John's College, Annapolis, MD

BA, Liberal Arts, 2002

Dominican University, Chicago, IL

Master of Library and Information Science, 2004

PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Web Development Intensive, **General Assembly**, April-July 2014 Front End Web Development, **General Assembly**, 2014 UX Research Methods, **University of Baltimore**, 2013 Introduction to Statistics, **Graduate School USA**, 2011 Data Journalism Bootcamp, **University of Missouri**, 2009 Presenting Data and Information, **Edward Tufte**, 2008

EXTRA-CURRICULAR

Freelance writer for **NPR**. Taught Excel class at **National Press Club**, July 2012 and January 2013. Reported a story for *All Things Considered* in 2009.